IL Cafe we have you covered
good to have you join us on Isle Cafe my
name
requires a lot of attention and focus
but perhaps in our country as I'm
realizing it doesn't get as much focus
and that is the area of Motor Vehicle
Insurance you know taken aback because
when you buy a car usually you know that
whole process of insurance is part of
the whole deal so I'm thinking who are
these people who somehow are managing
not to ensure their vehicles and why
would they do that but questions will
get answered it's a stunning Revelation
jury and it has of course led to a shift
in the approach to vehicle insurance uh
in India from the authorities as well as
insurance companies so that's you know
the silver lining in that particular
cloud in fact ICICI Lombard has been
among the innovators in this regard with
a roster of motor insurance products
that address pretty much all of these
issues now on this episode of oil Cafe I
thought we should you know arm ourselves
with wisdom and guidance and insight and
perspective so who better than nitin
Khanna business head motor business at
ICICI Lombard to join us and talk about
the shifting ground no pun intended in
the motor vehicle insurance sector in
India today and how that really impacts
vehicle owners themselves and also the
automobile industry in general so that's
really the context I wanted to give you
before I welcome nitin onto the show
Nathan thank you so much for making us
some time welcome to the show and how
are you thanks darling fine thanks for
having me here a pleasure entirely and I
have to ask you since we're talking
about Motors right I am reminded of the
very first set of wheels that I ever sat
on and that was a bicycle a BSA SLR that
my father bought for me as a as a gift
when I was in school what was yours I'm
curious to know did you what was a is
there a pet memory associated with the
first vehicle that you own I think you
said for most of us the first vehicle
would be cycle for which our parents
would have bought for us and even maybe
in our early teens right but what I
remember would be my first quarter which
I bought after I got my job which also
my dad got for me that's the first
automobile which I bought once I got my
job
so that was the first day yeah and while
the first one remains special actually
in our context of motor insurance every
vehicle after that remains as important
or should remain as important maybe if
you could tell us about some of the
ground realities of Motor Vehicle
Insurance in India a few things here I
think one if you have to divide
automobile into three different segments
there is a private car there's a tour
there's a commercial vehicles hmm
[Music]
so that also impacts the oral
engineering Champions these are some
interesting points over here with
respect to the distinction the type of
vehicles that you've made over here but
then that brings me to a more even more
fundamental question that I think all of
our listeners would benefit from why is
the need for therefore motor insurance
at all why is it necessary for a vehicle
owner to purchase insurance because you
know from the look of it you can make do
without it also you can pay for repairs
you know sell it for whatever price you
might get buy another vehicle uh so why
buy insurance for my car or bike or SUV
or any other vehicle if I can actually
manage to take good care of it
one is there a classic debate in terms
of self-insurance versus technical
Insurance
because we think that nothing will
happen going to happen to my homework
are still lower in this country
but if you look at how the automated
action when you get two parts there is
one which is the damage of the vehicle
and then the third party I feel that
damage to the vehicle that is largely
what people look at today the amount of
electronics or semiconductor which goes
into a car
accidents right so the cost of repair is
also going down so it makes a lot of
sense for people to ensure their vehicle
because of the even the OD damage if
yeah should end up beating somebody on a
road with a third party damage which in
India is unlimited I mean that code can
reward uh
any amount of regard to the personal
effective the nominee of the person is
affected and you have to pay that amount
the premiums are as low as five thousand
six thousand rupees for an old damage in
a private car and would be 700
so I would like to bear that liability
on you if you can get that through
insurance company by paying 700 rupees
yeah absolutely I think clearly there's
a huge Advantage for customer to view
the vehicle I think there's more of
inertia like I think they consumer not
they forget it then actually not doing
it yeah initial lethargy and also
probably lack of awareness for example
I'll tell you my own story for a long
time I didn't understand the third party
Insurance aspect of it in my own husband
one day took my Chavi and hit it in the
box and say oh you know I'm sorry but
you're not going to drive this car
because third party insurance is not
there and that's when I realize
you know so
um I think I'm hoping a podcast like
this or a show like this will go a long
way into building that level of
awareness into people you know one more
question that really I think begs to be
asked while we are understanding the
basics of the space nitin is the uh
industry size what are some of the India
specific information the market uh size
that you can give us to help us
understand why so much of focus is being
given to motor insurance as uh an area
mandatory product and when you buy a new
vehicle it is always insured that's if
you can't register a vehicle with an
insurance or the penetration was very
high temperature
and they're used to drive the overall uh
can you just continue for any insurance
company to invest in terms of Manpower
in terms of the technology in terms of
the new products that is our deal and if
you look at Indian market in terms of
the automobile we have the fastest
growing market today
M2 will be almost the largest market I
don't think any other country produces
like we do you're right it's a mode of
convenience for it a regular Indian
today is a two wheeler so it's all a
ripple effect in many ways and suddenly
like we're responding to that question I
realized that nitin must be the go-to
person for his family members
because you are such a subject matter
expert on even that areas of what is
available and what are the segments and
so on so that was fascinating to hear
more than actually advise on that more
for discounts
I think that is more which I get calls
for not for a device
I think two things today one is the
waiting period is very high can you make
it even faster and plus the discount
yeah so we have an insight into what
kind of phone calls also nitin is
feeling more stop more often than not
and well we'll take a small little break
and on the other side we'll talk about
some of the interesting products that
are being born of this consumer need
anything will tell us about both what
are these new expectations consumers
have and what are the products that icso
Lamar and organizations like uh this
actually have catered to or tailored for
these means stay with us on Isle Cafe
it's nitin Khanna who's joining us today
IL Cafe we have you covered
back again on Isle Cafe we are talking
about a very important area and that is
Motor Vehicle Insurance Now nitin
Products right we just spoke about the
realities the market realities some of
the trends Etc but it could be more
important for our listeners to
understand uh customer expectations and
products and how these two have aligned
to give us some of those great options
that you know icse Lombard is so famous
for the you know plethora or very
interesting products so if you could
tell us a little bit about both those
aspects it would be great so I think as
I said there are these are basic
insurance
or the accident but uh we are the
industry are very regulated till maybe a
year back I think was the newer
Community Development a lot of openness
in terms of finding of the production of
polymorphic products along with trans
people not new products right we also
didn't come here lost many products in
Lost
in helping the consumer to one
convenience and second also reducing
their premium in case they are driving
well if you look at the industry we used
to earlier price based on Factor like
class of the vehicle
or the location so we used to assume
Indica in Delhi is a bad vehicle but
there could be indications given by
maybe a businessman Syndicate is also
driven by for example Indica I used to
type in PR 10 kilometers a day the
another guy was a better finish to drive
I will keep them safe those hard
industry was kind of surprisingly uh the
insurance for quite some time in the
last one year a lot of that has changed
we also have products which link your
civil score to your insurance premiums I
can understand timing Behavior to
various mode I can either put every
Divine in your car which will give me
the data in terms of your sudden
breaking your sharp turns your time of
driving how much you drive and all that
can help me to price you better so I can
price let's say anything cannot
different from sheetal because I know
sheetal drives much more safer than
anything and now who is arising
similarly I can also say okay with
somebody who drives
in a lot of our family there are two or
three vectors our Bombay it might be a
lesser Trend but if you go to Delhi if
there are five adults in a family there
are five cars right or maybe four cars
and one bike based on the family uh
demographic and you can ensure all the
products that you said you might forget
to renew your policy if you have five
card you might forget to do one policy
right but now I can we can ensure all
your vehicles in your family in one way
in one policy that gives you a lot of
convenience for not remembering all
these children dates and going for
insurance on one course you can ensure
all the vehicles
right we do the analysis of symbol along
with the loss issue behavior of the
consumer in life that a good civil score
customer is also a better loss so maybe
it drives better so there are a lot of
episodes there but they will kill a
correlation between
a billboard civil score and a good
driver okay if your civil score in more
than 750 which is considerably good
civil score will give you a distant
discount on your premium so that you can
renew your vehicles all the new products
are coming in the market now we have
taken some lead in terms of watching
this product but my sense no other
player will also start launching these
products fantastic you know of all the
information that given us in terms of
the products available and some of the
benefits and how they are speaking or
addressing specific needs of the
customer so a hyper personalized if I
may put it that way one thing that also
stood out which I really like from you
is even if it was an example you use it
sheetal is a very good driver so I want
to take that part of the recording I
want to play to all my family members
for prostate posterity so there's no
doubt or debate on the matter coming
from nitin Khanna himself and on that
happy note it's time to wrap up Isle
Cafe it's been a fun conversation
understanding an area that I think
touches all of our Lives all of us know
at least somebody who owns a vehicle
even if we don't own one ourselves so
far and this kind of information is
critical in helping us make those
choices and decisions thank you so much
nitin for joining us on oil Cafe today
and helping us understand the space
thank you thank you very much
thank you you were listening to Il Cafe
we have you covered
[Music]
foreign